

# Hi, my name is **Geert Pasteels** and I'm a creative full-stack web developer.

**\( +32 472 26 24 24** 

☑ geert.pasteels@gmail.com

9 3190 Boortmeerbeek, Belgium

#### Languages

Dutch

\*\*\*\*

**English** 

**★★★☆** 

French

\*\*\*\*

• Profiles •

**G**ithub

Stackoverflow

• Interests •

**Sports** 

Cycling, Running

Bread

Sourdough, Flat, Pizza

Fishing

## About me

Since 2006, I've been a full stack developer, with a focus on creating effective websites and applications. My approach combines a strong front-end development skill set with a solid understanding of back-end technologies.

I prioritize clear communication and understanding your needs, whether it's a new project from scratch or improving an existing one, I'm ready to tackle your web development challenges with expertise and enthusiasm.

For an extended version of this resume visit https://geertpasteels.be

## Skills

#### **Proficient**

\*\*\*

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, React.js, Tailwind, Data Viz, Create React App, Design Systems, Node.js, Express.js, Vite, Webpack, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Git, Monorepo, PostgreSQL, Snowflake, Docker, Portainer, Openshift, VS Code, Vim, Emacs, Affinity Designer, Fedora, Ubuntu, macOS, Windows, JIRA, Gitlab, Github

#### Comfortable

\*\*\*

TypeScript, Python, Storybook, Adonis.js, Next.js, Flask, Django, OpenAPI, Puppeteer, SQLite, Cockpit, ZFS, NGIX, Traefik, VFIO, Figma

#### Familiar

★☆☆

CI/CD, Kubernetes

# Experience

## Cisco Systems, Inc

Full-stack Developer

Remote

2014 - 2024

A global leader in design and manufacture of internet communications technologies (ICT) and services, with >70,000 employees in 90 countries and annual revenue of \$47 billion

Interface & UX Designer, Architect, Full stack JavaScript, Python Developer & Infrastructure

Full-stack developer for the internal applications.

- Successfully led JavaScript design for Cisco's CaseMaker software, a web tool for generating customer-facing and Forrester Research-certified financial business cases, in support of >\$500 million in annual service revenue
- Support for redesign of CaseMaker customer-facing outputs, ensuring usability and intuitive understanding of financial outputs through improvements on data and information visualisation.
- Technical coordination of CaseMaker development in accordance with Cisco data security rules and IT policy
- Developed a deal monitoring system for over 60,000 active renewals, equipping renewals managers with automatically generated business reports to counteract discount pressure.

#### **Wolf's Little Store**

Full-stack Developer

Remote

2013 - 2014

Belgian company that specializes in digital product design with a strong prototyping methodology.

- Helped creating a JavaScript transition plugin for the open-source prototyping framework Clank.
- Creating a command line tool with Node.js for extracting data from OSX ICAL that's used for accounting.

# UnderdogDesign

Front-end Developer

Remote

2012 - 2014

New media company that specializes in creating designs and working websites for one of Belgium's largest producer of children's television series and amusement parks.

- Converting designs for Studio100 most popular children's television series into working websites with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Browser game (platform) for one of the Studio100 characters using the game framework Phaser.js.

## **TwoToTango**

Full-stack Developer

2011 - 2012

Remote

Peter Eysermans is a freelance professional with a strong knowledge of the .NET ecosystem, Agile and Test Driven Development

• Creating the social platform Bookido.be for book lovers and bookstores. Social users of the site can follow other users, rate books, get recommendations, search and buy books from Belgian bookstores through an e-commerce platform.

#### **DeWitMedia**

Full-stack Developer

Remote

2001 - 2014

Creative communications company with a strong focus on visual design ranging from large format printing to web solutions.

- Creating a CMS backed website for Wicreations one of Belgian's largest designers in custom stages for the entertainment industry.
- Creating and consulting on newsletters for a high-end clothing store.

# Education

#### The Clean Coders Screencasts

Screencasts

A video course by Uncle Bob Martin for writing better professional applications with a strong focus on the SOLID design principals.

https://cleancoders.com

# **Destroy All Software**

Screencasts

These videos give concrete examples on how to write applications using TDD, GIT and the Unix platform.

## Clojure for the Brave and True

Book

This is an online book for learning the Clojure functional programming language. Functional programming languages like Clojure/Clojurescript and Elm pioneered state management systems which to this day are still used in front- end development.

https://www.braveclojure.com

#### Intec

Brussels Web Development 2004 - 2005

#### **TSM**

Mechelen Graphic Design 1998 to 2002

## References

## Ramyasri Sriramulu

Project Manager at Cisco Systems https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramyasri-sriramulu

## **Ivor Barker**

Senior Manager at Cisco Systems https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivor-barker-569260/